Cathedral College Collection: Class of 1924
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Cathedral College Collection: Class of 1924
1918 – 1924
NPKMC-223-107
1 Linear Foot
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
The Class of 1924 at Cathedral College.
The History of Cathedral College’s Class of 1924 consists of various items which depict the years spent at Cathedral College by the class of 1924. The collection contains a book describing the members of the class, the professors, and what happened during the years, with some photographs. There are also newsletters printed by the members of the class describing the latest occurrences as well as jokes, and a few postcards.
Collection Overview
The History of Cathedral College’s Class of 1924 consists of a book written by the class detailing their lives at school, newsletters printed up and distributed by the class, as well as photographs of the students and postcards received by the students.
The Cathedral College Collection of 1924 was donated to Marist College.
Biographical Note
Cathedral College in New York, NY was a prep school for possible priesthood candidates. Boys attended the school for six years. The time spent by the boys of the class of 1924 spanned from 1918 through 1924.
There are no restrictions on this collection
Arrangement of the Collection
These records are organized into two series: 1) Class Newsletters, and 2) Record Book
Materials in each series maintain their original order or are arranged chronologically.
- 1. Class Newsletters, 1; 1 linear foot 1 1 - 18
  The Class Newsletters span from 1919 through 1920.
  Original order/chronologically
  - Vol. I. February 24, 1919. No. 1., 1.1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Copy of Vol. I. February 24, 1919. No. 1., 1.2 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Vol. I. No. 2., 2.1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Copy of Vol. I. No. 2., 2.2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Vol. I. No. 3., 3.1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Copy of Vol I. No. 3., 3.2 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Vol. I. No. 4. Poetry Edition., 4.1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Copy of Vol. I. No. 4. Poetry Edition., 4.2 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Vol. I. No. 5., 5.1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Copy of Vol. I. No. 5., 5.2 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Vol. II. Mon. October 13, 1919. No. 1., 6.1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Copy of Vol. II. Mon. October 13, 1919. No. 1., 6.2 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Vol. II. Mon. November 5, 1919. No. 2., 7.1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Copy of Vol. II. Mon. November 5, 1919. No. 2., 7.2 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Vol. II. No. 3., 8 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Vol. II. Dec. 19, 1919. No. 4. Christmas Edition, 9.1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Copy of Vol. II. Dec. 19, 1919. No. 4. Christmas Edition., 9.2 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Maude (cartoon drawing) by OTHS., 10 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Vol. II. Feb. 24, 1920. Anniversary Edition. No. 5., 11.1 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Copy of Vol. II. Feb. 24, 1920. Anniversary Edition. No. 5., 11.2 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Vol. II. March 12, 1920. No. 6., 12 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Vol. II. April 23, 1920. No. 7., 13.1 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Copy of Vol. II. April 23, 1920. No. 7., 13.2 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Vol. II. May 18, 1920. Farewell Edition. No. 8., 14.1 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Copy of Vol. II. May 18, 1920. Farewell Edition. No. 8., 14.2 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Vol. III. October 22, 1920. No. 1., 15 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Dec. 11, 1920., 16 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Not dated. No. 5?, 17.1 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Copy of Not dated. No. 5 ?, 17.2 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Not dated., 18 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- 2. Record Book, 2; 1 linear foot 1 19
  The Record Book is the class’s history, a written account of the class of 1924’s years at Cathedral College, from their freshmen year in 1919 until their senior year and graduation in 1924. It contains biographies of all the members of the class, descriptions of the activities participated in, everyday activities and the yearly class outings, jokes, photographs of class outings and the members of the class.
  Original order
  - Class History Book (Folder 19, Box 2)